Ahmed Khaled A. Awwad

SOC Analyst Tier 1

n Ahmed Awwad 🔗 Blog 🜓 Military service: Completed

Electronics and Communication Engineer, Jr SOC Analyst with 1 year of experience in analysis and cooperation in incident investigations. seeking to leverage my skills in a challenging SOC Analyst Tier 1 role. Committed to enhancing systems' security tools by utilizing advanced threat detection techniques, incident response strategies. In order to achieve that I consider myself as self-learner, self-motivated, and dedicated to pursuing my goals to build a focused career.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Communication and Electronics Engineering,

2016 - 2022

Faculty of Engineering Helwan University
Project: Email Anti-spammer system

☑

Degree: Excellent

EXPERIENCE

Armed Forces

SOC Analyst Jul 2023 | Confidential

Monitor OSSIM SIEM, maintain and developed **Kaspersky** server and managed devices. Ensuring protection against malware and cyber threats.

Network and Systems Administrator

Jul 2023 | Confidential

Manage all military **internal network**, systems, also configure and **maintain** their devices.

Optima Professional Services (OPS)

SOC Analyst Jul 2023 – 2024 | Part time

SOC Analyst | Tier 1

Oct 2022 - May 2023 | Full time

Monitor and analyze incidents. Analyzing Business environment and traffic **baseline** to enhance SOAR playbooks to reduce **False-Positive** repeated incident rate. Also help reduced incident **response time** through efficient monitoring and analysis. **Follow-up** with the IT Teams and other business units to develop action plans to mitigate identified vulnerabilities.

Excel Codes, Back-end Developer intern □

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

"ICenna 🛮 " Website and Mobile Application

Back-End Developer for Python (Django) for websites and apps.

Freelancer, Curriculum writer

Aug 2017 - Jan 2019

Physics & Mathematics content writer, booklets content designing and translating Arabic content to English

COURSES & INTERNSHIPS

Cyber Security Engineer, <i>Udacity</i> ☑	Jul 2022 – Nov 2022
CCNAv7, National Telecommunication Institute (NTI) ☑	Oct 2022 – Nov 2022
Foundations of Operation MITRE ATT&CK, ATTACKIQ Academy	Sep 2022
Cyber Security Engineer Intern, VTF ☑	May 2022 – Jul 2022
Intro to IT & Cybersecurity, Cybrary ☑	May 2021
CEH & Pentesting Fundamentals, Trend Micro & CyberTalents ☑	Jun 2021 – Aug 2021
Full Stack Web Developer, Udacity 🗹	Nov 2017 – Feb 2018
Front-End Web Developer, Udacity	Nov 2017 – Feb 2018

SKILLS

SIEM Solutions | EDR | SOAR

Incidents Investigation

Infrastructure & System Security

Application & Network Security

Linux | Cryptography | R&D

Network & Systems administration

Programming

Python, Bash, C++..

Technical Reporting/Writing

SOFT SKILLS

Verbal Communication

Adapt with work environments | Team Work

Negotiation skills

Self Learner | Time Management

Problem solving

Critical and Logical Thinking

Business acumen | Customer Service Orientation

LANGUAGES

Arabic

Mother tongue

English

B2-Upper Intermediate

• • • •

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

PROJECTS

Spamurai, *Graduation project* □

Spamurai is **Email Anti-spammer** system in cyber security field. It is Research and development (**R&D**) project aim to find and implement a solution to **detect and prevent** or lessen the interaction of users with any adware, **harmful/spam emails** based on content analysis as URL, TEXT and Files using AI Machine learning to analysis and prediction.

Auxilio Robotic, IEEE RAS, Certificate □

control team leader. Our objective is to structure **Line follower Robot**, automatically or manually.